While transporting the man they've
在押送他们绑架的男子途中
kidnapped, Vahed's van breaks down.
，瓦赫德的货车抛锚了。
When they resort to pushing the van
当他们不得不推着货车
through the busy streets of Tehran,
穿过德黑兰繁忙的街道时，
the scene is shot in an unusual way
这一幕以一种不同寻常的方式拍摄下来，
with the camera hidden on a nearby
摄像机隐藏在附近的
rooftop.
屋顶上。
This is done for an important reason.
这样做是有重要原因的。
In another scene, Shiva gets out of the
在另一个场景中，希瓦下车去
van to go speak with someone. As she
和某人交谈。 当她
crosses the street and begins arguing
穿过马路并开始
with the man, the camera does something
与该男子争吵时，摄像机出现了
strange.
奇怪的现象。
It stays inside.
它留在里面。
These are just two of the many signs
这只是众多迹象中的两个，表明
that the film was shot in secret to
这部电影是秘密拍摄的，以
avoid the detection of the Iranian
避免被伊朗
government.
政府发现。
Much of it was just an accident. The
很多事情都只是意外。
latest film from Jafar Panahi, nominated
贾法·帕纳西的最新电影
for two Oscars this year, takes place in
今年获得了两项奥斯卡提名，故事发生在
more remote locations.
较为偏远的地方。
In places like this, you can stage
在这样的地方，你可以安排人
lookouts to alert the filmmakers so they
放哨，以便在警察出现时提醒电影制作人员
can hide the cameras if the police come
藏匿摄像机
along.
。
But when shooting in more populated
但在人口更密集的地区拍摄时
areas, the camera almost always stays
，摄像机几乎总是
hidden inside a car.
隐藏在车内。
This doesn't stem from unwarranted
这并非源于毫无根据的
paranoia. By the time Panahi was making
妄想。 帕纳希拍摄
this movie, he had already been to
这部电影时，他已经因为
prison for filmmaking twice.
拍电影入狱两次了。   在
And as he promotes the film abroad, he's
他出国宣传这部电影的同时，他
for him upon his return to Iran.
返回伊朗后将面临第三次牢狱之灾。
Despite this undercover approach, it's
尽管采用了这种隐秘的拍摄手法，但令人
surprising how little effect it has on
惊讶的是，它对整部电影的影响却很小
the overall film.
。
If you weren't paying close attention,
如果你不仔细观察，
you might not even notice. Yet the
可能根本不会注意到。 然而，
effortlessness with which Panahi now
帕纳希如今如此轻松自如地
wields this clandestine style didn't
运用这种隐秘风格，并非
arrive overnight.
一朝一夕就能实现的。
For many directors, a 6-year prison
对于许多导演来说，因涉嫌从事反政权宣传活动而被判处 6 年
sentence and a 20-year ban on filmmaking
监禁和 20 年电影制作禁令，
against the regime would be enough to
足以
make them change careers or flee the
让他们改行或逃离该
country. But after his ban, Panahi, who
国。 但被禁之后，当时
had already been a director for 15 years
已经做了 15 年导演的帕纳希
just kept making movies.
仍然继续拍电影。
At first, he tentatively tested the
起初，他只是试探性地试探一下
waters.
。
This is not a film which shot within the
这不是一部在
confines of Panahi's apartment and was
帕纳希的公寓里拍摄，然后
smuggled out of the country to the
偷偷运出国参加
Cannes Film Festival.
戛纳电影节的电影。
But by Taxi, his third film made
但到了他的第三部非法拍摄的电影《出租车》时
illegally, he had become bold enough to
，他已经大胆到可以
shoot within the semi-public setting of
在半公共的汽车环境中进行拍摄
a car.
。
This is a metafiction about himself as a
这是一部以他自己为
taxi driver. The story is told through
出租车司机的元小说。 故事是通过
Panahi's interactions with the different
帕纳希
passengers as he drives through the
驾车穿过城市时与不同乘客的互动来讲述的
city. One scene from the film explicitly
。 影片中有一个场景明确地
addresses the strict content guidelines
谈到了伊朗对
placed on any film that screens legally
任何合法上映的电影都制定的严格内容准则
in Iran.
。
Perhaps particularly relevant to
或许与
Panahi's work are the limits placed on
帕纳希的作品特别相关的，是对
so-called sordid realism.
所谓“肮脏现实主义”的限制。
By the time he shot No Bears in 2022,
到 2022 年拍摄《没有熊》时，
he'd become bold enough to shoot
他已经胆子大到可以
outdoors in rural areas, skipping from
在农村地区进行户外拍摄，
one small village to another anytime the
只要警察来搜查，他就从一个村庄跳到另一个村庄
police came looking.
。
This time telling a fictionalized
这次他讲述了一个虚构的
version of how he goes about making his
故事，关于他如何
films in secret.
秘密地制作电影。
It was after this film that he would
这部电影之后，他
land in prison for a second time.
第二次锒铛入狱。
Vahid has kidnapped a man with a false
瓦希德绑架了一名装有
leg.
假肢的男子。
He suspects this captive is someone who
他怀疑这个俘虏就是当年
tortured him in prison.
在监狱里折磨他的人。
But as the man protests, Vahid to doubt.
但随着男子的抗议，瓦希德开始怀疑。
&gt;&gt; [panting]
[喘息]
&gt;&gt; He wants revenge, but he does not want
他想复仇，但他不想
to harm an innocent man.
伤害无辜的人。
So he starts tracking down some other
于是他开始寻找其他曾被
prisoners who were tormented by the same
同一绑架者折磨过的囚犯，
captor in order to verify he has the
以确认自己抓对了
correct person.
人。
This is the setup for the rest of the
这是影片其余部分的铺垫
film, which is one of the best of last
，也是去年最好的电影之一
year. It's full of suspense, a
。 它充满了悬念，
surprising amount of humor, and it
出人意料地幽默，并且
ultimately grapples with the central
最终探讨了核心
question.
问题。
How do you respond to people who have
你会如何回应那些曾经
oppressed you? When is violence or
压迫过你的人？ 暴力或
revenge justified? [music]
复仇在什么情况下才是正当的？  [音乐]
This ethical question that runs through
贯穿整部电影核心的这个伦理问题，
hypothetical thought experiment for
对于
Panahi or the other Iranians on screen.
帕纳希或其他出现在银幕上的伊朗人来说，并不是一个假设性的思想实验。
Panahi based the movie on his
帕纳希根据自己的
experiences in prison and the stories he
狱中经历和在
heard there.
那里听到的故事创作了这部电影。
But it is not just the film's real-world
但这部电影引人入胜之处不仅仅在于它与现实世界的
political relevance that make it
政治关联
compelling. It is the perspective that
。
Panahi takes on these issues, the way he
帕纳希对这些问题的看法和
presents it, that I find most
表达方式，最令我
interesting.
感兴趣。
His perspective not just on politics and
他的观点不仅关乎政治和
violence, but on human beings.
暴力，更关乎人性。
A young girl walks the streets of Tehran
一名年轻女孩独自走在德黑兰的街头
alone.
。
She's trying to make her way home since
由于
her mother didn't show up to pick her up
妈妈没有来学校接她，她正试图自己回家
from school.
。
This is Panahi's second film, The
这是帕纳希的第二部电影，《
Mirror.
镜子》。
It would be the last movie Panahi would
这将是帕纳希最后一部
make without any legal trouble.
没有遇到任何法律纠纷的电影。
define his work are already present.
他作品中许多后来成为其标志性特征的元素已经显现。
Most notably, the way he sees humanity
最值得注意的是，他看待人类
and the world around him.
和周围世界的方式。
His ability to capture that vision on
他有能力将这种景象用
film.
电影呈现出来。
It's an incredible movie, one I want
这是一部非常棒的电影，我希望
more people to watch, and it's half the
更多的人能够观看，这也是
reason I wanted to make this video.
我制作这个视频的原因之一。
On the surface, The Mirror is about this
从表面上看，《镜子》讲述的是一个
young girl and her journey.
年轻女孩的成长历程。
We watch the whole film play out at her
我们以她的视角观看了整部电影
eye level. When she interacts with
。 当她与
adults, we often don't see their faces.
成年人互动时，我们通常看不到他们的脸。
The camera isn't observing her from
镜头不是从
inside the world of adults, but from
成人的世界里观察她，而是从
within her world. And by doing this, the
她的世界里观察她。 这样做，
city around us takes on the kind of
我们周围的城市就会呈现出一种
overwhelming force that a young child
幼童
would face.
会面临的强大力量。
But this unfolds with a great deal of
但事情的发展远比想象中复杂得多
nuance. It's not just a story about the
。 这不仅仅是一个关于孩子面对
frightening reality of the city
城市可怕现实的故事
confronting the child. It's also about
。 这同时也展现了
her courage, independence, and even
她的勇气、独立性，以及
competence in navigating the space.
在这个领域游刃有余的能力。
There's another side to the story that
故事还有另一面，
lends it even more depth, and that's the
使其更具深度，那就是
surrounds her.
她所处世界的质感和真实感。
We see Tehran with a kind of documentary
我们以一种纪录片式的
realism.
现实主义视角来看待德黑兰。
We overhear many conversations between
我们经常听到大人之间的对话
adults.
。
And in the periphery of this child's
在这个孩子
journey home, we glimpse a nuanced
回家的旅程中，我们得以窥见
portrait of a place.
一个地方的细致入微的景象。
Through Panahi's eyes, as he gives us
透过帕纳希的眼睛，他以
the perspective of a child, we see
孩子的视角，让我们
clearly the humanity of the city. The
清晰地看到这座城市的人性。
people portrayed here aren't a singular
这里描绘的人物并非单一的
homogeneous mass, but a collection of
同质群体，而是一群
individuals with different perspectives
拥有不同观点
and ways of existing within the
和生存方式的个体，
constraints their society has placed on
他们都受到社会强加于他们的各种限制
them.
。
What I find impressive about Panahi's
帕纳希作品最令我印象深刻的
work is that he offers this kind of
是，他能
nuance to every character he portrays.
为他所塑造的每一个角色赋予这种微妙的层次感。
of It Was Just an Accident is the first
第一次听的时候，你可能不会意识到《这只是一场意外》的开头有多么大胆
time around.
。
You simply meet a man driving his family
你偶然遇到一个深夜开车送家人
home late at night.
回家的男人。
They accidentally hit a dog.
他们不小心撞到了一只狗。
And after some car trouble, they stop to
汽车发生故障后，他们停下来
get help.
寻求帮助。
This is where Vahid recognizes the sound
瓦希德就是在这里认出了
of the leg.
腿的声音。   对于
first-time viewer, Vahid seems like he
初次观看这部电影的观众来说，从目前了解到的情况来看，瓦希德似乎像是
might be the villain of the film.
电影中的反派角色。
The man he kidnaps doesn't seem
他绑架的那个人看起来并不
particularly threatening or evil. It's
特别具有威胁性或邪恶。
only later we hear about how horrible of
后来我们才知道
a person he might be.
他可能是个多么可怕的人。
Just in case it's not clear, the movie
以防万一还不清楚，
Panahi makes fresh out of prison opens
帕纳希出狱后拍摄的这部电影，开篇就将
represents the captor.
代表绑架者的角色人性化了。
Later, as the characters are arguing
后来，当剧中人物揭露了他们作为囚犯遭受的残酷对待的真相后，他们正在争论
about what to do with their suspected
如何处置他们怀疑的
tormentor after they reveal the stark
折磨者
treated as prisoners. As they're
。 就在他们
debating the kind of punishment he
讨论他应该受到什么样的惩罚时
deserves,
，
it's at this very moment that Panahi
帕纳希
chooses to remind us of something.
选择提醒我们一些事情。
I don't see this as a shallow attempt to
我不认为这是肤浅地试图
subvert our expectations or build
颠覆我们的预期或制造
suspense. Panahi is simply bringing the
悬念。 帕纳希只是想让
violence to our attention. They know
我们注意到任何暴力行为的后果。 他们知道，
that if they harm this guy, they'll risk
如果伤害这个人，就有可能
harming his innocent daughter. They know
伤害到他无辜的女儿。 他们知道，
that to help his daughter, they'll put
为了帮助他的女儿，他们会把
themselves at risk. The question it
自己置于危险之中。 它
leaves us with, perhaps the most
留给我们一个问题，或许也是
relevant question to the world right
当今世界最相关的问题
now, is whether it is ever justifiable
，那就是：
to knowingly allow the innocent to be
明知故犯地让无辜者受到
harmed.
伤害，这种行为是否正当？
To treat a child as collateral damage.
将儿童视为附带损害。
I was in the middle of editing this
我正在剪辑这段
video when the United States and Israel
视频的时候，美国和以色列
decided to start bombing Iran. One bomb
决定开始轰炸伊朗。 其中一枚炸弹
killed Ali Khamenei, the supreme leader
炸死了伊朗最高领袖阿里·哈梅内伊
of Iran, who just recently presided over
，他不久前刚刚下令
the massacre of tens of thousands of
屠杀了数万名
protesters.
抗议者。
Another bomb, which early reports are
另一枚炸弹（初步报告
indicating was most likely launched by
显示很可能是美国发射的）
struck a girls' school, killing over 100
击中了一所女子学校，造成 100 多名
civilians, most of them children. It is
平民死亡，其中大部分是儿童。
significance of "it was just an
“这只是一场意外”这句话的含义和重要性，
that is still unfolding as I make this
与我制作这段视频时仍在不断发展的政治背景是无法割裂开来的
video. It would be similarly impossible
。 同样，
for me to give an accurate, thorough,
我也不可能在这段关于一部电影的视频中，对所有相关的背景信息给出准确、全面
and nuanced account of all of that
和细致的描述
movie. Neither I nor It Was Just an
。 我和“这只是一场
Accident have easy answers for what is
意外”组织都无法对这种
an incredibly complex situation. What
极其复杂的情况给出简单的答案。
Panahi does do with this movie is ask
帕纳希在这部电影中提出了
some incredibly difficult questions that
一些极其棘手的问题，这些问题
are very relevant to everything that's
与
happening now. Even without this
现在发生的一切息息相关。 即使不考虑这一
context, the question of justice and
背景，正义与
nonviolence is already an incredibly
非暴力问题本身就是一个极其
fraught subject. In It Was Just an
棘手的话题。 在《这只是一场
Accident, Panahi tackles this subject in
意外》中，帕纳希以大胆的方式处理了这个主题，
a daring way by doing what he's always
他一如既往地
done, showing things in their
展现了事物
uncomfortable complexity without
令人不安的复杂性，而没有将
reducing things to the binary of
事物简化为
political propaganda. He tries to view
政治宣传的二元对立。 他试图
the conflict not through abstract
不通过抽象的
narratives, but by seeing the humanity
叙事来看待这场冲突，而是通过看到
of each person involved.
每个相关人员的人性来看待这场冲突。
This, of course, is an easy way to upset
当然，这样做很容易惹恼
people because while you're trying to
别人，因为虽然你想
see the humanity in all of these
从所有这些角度看到人性
perspectives, you cannot force the
，但你不能强迫
viewer into siding with a particular
观众支持某种特定的
view. When some or even both of the
观点。 当涉事双方或其中一方
parties involved have committed
犯下
incredible atrocity,
令人难以置信的暴行时，将
humanizing them or anyone associated
他们或与他们有关的人人化，
with them can feel like the worst
可能会让人觉得是最糟糕的
possible thing.
事情。
For those who see their view as the
对于那些将自身观点视为
objective truth that must be fought for,
必须捍卫的客观真理的人来说，
anything other than a total commitment
任何偏离
to that view can feel like a betrayal of
该观点的行为都会让他们感到背叛了
everything they believe in. This is even
自己所信仰的一切。而
propaganda plays in all of this. I have
宣传在其中扮演的角色，更使情况变得复杂起来。 我
seen expressed on every type of media
看到各种媒体，从各种角度
expressing every kind of perspective on
看待
this conflict the accusation of
这场冲突，都出现了指责
propaganda for one side or the other.
对方进行宣传的言论。
And it's made me wonder, is it even
这让我不禁思考，
possible for an artist to engage with a
艺术家是否有可能以一种
topic like this in a way that isn't
不带
propagandistic? How does an artist or
宣传色彩的方式来探讨这样的话题？ 艺术家或
film navigate these waters? Can you even
电影如何应对这些挑战？ 你能否在不
differing views without resorting to a
诉诸于
watered-down both-sides-ism that tries
淡化的“双方都一样”主义，不试图用
to use neutrality as an escape from
中立来逃避
uncomfortable questions?
棘手问题的情况下，认真对待不同观点的复杂性和细微差别？
Jafar Panahi does not consider himself a
贾法尔·帕纳西并不认为自己是一位
political filmmaker, choosing instead to
政治电影导演，而是
call himself a social director. But I
称自己为一位社会导演，这或许会让你感到惊讶。 但我
want to be clear, I don't think this is
想澄清一点，我认为这并非像
artists recently who naively hope their
最近一些艺术家那样，天真地希望自己的
work can be apolitical when ultimately
作品可以不涉及政治，从而试图标榜中立，而实际上
any perspective has political
任何观点最终都具有政治
implications. Instead, I think this has
含义。 相反，我认为这
to do with how Panahi approaches
与帕纳希
politics through his work. What I think
通过他的作品来探讨政治的方式有关。 我认为这是
is the core of how he avoids creating
他避免制造
propaganda. But if this is possible, how
宣传的核心所在。 但如果这真的可行，该如何
can it be done? What sets a piece of
实现呢？
political propaganda apart from a movie
政治宣传片与以艺术方式
that engages with political ideas in an
探讨政治理念的电影有何区别
artful way? In a recent interview, he
？ 在最近的一次采访中，他
said, "In my definition, a political
说道：“在我看来，政治
filmmaker is somebody who belongs to a
电影制作人就是隶属于某个
party and who defends a specific
政党并捍卫某种特定
ideology. So they make a film that
意识形态的人。因此，他们制作的电影旨在
defends their ideology in which the good
捍卫他们的意识形态，电影中的
people are the people who observe and
好人是那些遵守和
respect this ideology, and the bad
尊重这种意识形态的人，而坏人则
people are those who are against them."
是那些反对这种意识形态的人。”
Propaganda works by crafting a narrative
宣传的运作方式是精心炮制一种叙事，将
that simplifies complex realities into
复杂的现实简化为二元
reductive binaries [music]
对立的二元对立[音乐]，
by portraying one side as so
将一方描绘成
irredeemably evil that violent force is
无可救药的邪恶，暴力是
the only option left, and then
唯一的选择，然后将
portraying the other side as already
另一方描绘成无论
justified in whatever they do because
他们做什么都是正当的，因为
they're inherently on the side of good.
他们本质上站在正义的一边。
If Panahi seems to condemn anything in
如果帕纳希在他的电影中似乎谴责了什么
his films, it's not specific people or
，那也不是具体的个人或
parties, but instead the underlying
政党，而是导致
to those people or parties taking
这些人或政党采取
harmful action. I don't think this is an
有害行为的潜在思维体系或观念。 我不认为这是
attempt to ignore the harm that
试图忽视
individuals or parties may have done.
个人或团体可能造成的伤害。
Instead, I see it as an attempt to get
相反，我认为这是一种试图
to the root cause of the issue. This is
找出问题根源的尝试。
the tension that's revealed in the film
影片
through Shiva and the heat's skepticism
通过湿婆和热浪
of their own violent impulses.
对自身暴力冲动的怀疑，揭示了这种紧张关系。
The heat and Shiva know they've suffered
热浪和湿婆知道他们遭受了
an injustice and they have a completely
不公正待遇，他们完全可以
understandable desire to seek justice by
理解地想要通过向他们
taking revenge on the man they believe
认为
was their captor, but they also know it
是绑架他们的人复仇来寻求正义，但他们也知道，
was their captor's system of thinking,
正是绑架者的思维体系，
that he bought into, that allowed him to
他所接受的政治和意识形态叙事，使他能够
strip them of their humanity so he could
剥夺他们的人性，从而为
justify violence against them. They want
对他们的暴力行为辩护。 他们想要
to be sure they don't fall prey to the
确保自己不会落入
that their oppressor did. The logic of
压迫者那种非人道逻辑的陷阱。 宣传的逻辑
propaganda relies on dehumanization,
依赖于非人化，将
flattening the people involved into
相关人员扁平化为
background characters, extras, or NPCs
背景角色、群众演员或NPC，
in a simplified story about nations and
简化讲述国家和
geopolitics. Panahi defies this by
地缘政治的故事。 帕纳希之所以反驳这种观点，是因为他没有
looking through those political
看穿这些政治
narratives
叙事，
not because they don't matter. They're
并不是因为它们不重要。 它们
incredibly influential on people's
对人们的
well-being and the course of the world,
福祉和世界走向有着巨大的影响，
but we also need opportunities to see
但我们也需要有机会将
the people inside those narratives as
这些故事中的人物视为
people, as human beings like ourselves.
人，视为和我们一样的人类。
To do this, he adopts a humanizing
为此，他采取了人性化的
perspective, and it's that humanizing
视角，而正是这种人性化的
perspective that stands in direct
视角
contrast to both propaganda and violent
与宣传和暴力
political narratives. Through these
政治叙事形成了鲜明的对比。 通过这些
characters, he even goes so far as to
人物，他甚至开始
wonder if we should offer this
思考我们是否应该用这种
humanizing lens to our worst enemies.
人性化的视角来看待我们最痛恨的敌人。
Not because they shouldn't be held
不是因为他们不应该为
accountable for wrongs they do commit,
自己犯下的错误承担责任，
but because how can we expect them to
而是因为
respect our humanity if we refuse to
如果我们拒绝
acknowledge their own? This is the
承认他们的人性，又怎能指望他们尊重我们的人性呢？ 这是《
question the Heat and Shiva have to
热血》和《湿婆》
grapple with in this film, and you'll
在这部电影中必须面对的问题，你
have to watch the movie to see how
必须观看这部电影才能知道
Panahi tries to resolve this.
帕纳希是如何尝试解决这个问题的。
But I think it's important to note that
但我认为值得注意的是，
Panahi doesn't ask these questions
帕纳希提出这些问题并非
lightly. He does not consider
轻率之举。 他并不
non-violence naively. He also humanizes
天真地看待非暴力。 他也从人性的
the perspective of those who have
角度看待那些
experienced so much injustice that
遭受过太多不公正待遇、以至于
non-violence feels impossible. A
觉得非暴力是不可能的人的视角。
non-violent path hopes that freedom and
非暴力道路希望
peace can be found by define the logic
通过定义武力的逻辑来找到自由与和平
of force. It hopes that humanizing tools
。 它希望通过
like compassion, understanding, and the
同情、理解和
revelation of truth can undermine the
揭示真相等人道主义工具，来削弱
dehumanizing logic of violent
暴力压迫的非人道逻辑
oppression. If there's any hope in this
。 如果这条道路还有任何希望的话
path, compassionate art is one of the
，那么充满同情心的艺术就是
most powerful tools it has at its
它所拥有的最强大的工具之一
disposal. Authoritarian governments
。 专制政府从
understand this inherently. That's why
本质上就明白这一点。 这就是为什么
they try so hard to control or censor
他们如此努力地控制或审查
art. That's why they view a camera in
艺术的原因。 这就是为什么他们认为
the hands of a citizen as such a threat.
公民手中的相机是一种威胁。
Panahi doesn't just use It was just an
帕纳希并非只是利用
accident to [music] ask these difficult
音乐的偶然性来提出这些棘手的
questions.
问题。
It is itself a question waiting to be
这本身就是一个有待
answered. Panahi has offered his film as
解答的问题。 帕纳希将他的电影视为
a form of non-violent dissent. And as he
一种非暴力异议的形式。 当他
returns to Iran with a third prison
带着第三次牢狱之灾的判决返回伊朗时
sentence hanging over his head, he
，他仍在
awaits an answer to his own question
等待着自己心中那个问题的答案：
consequences of that kind of dissent
这种异议的有效性和后果究竟如何
will be.
。
Art critic John Berger talks about
艺术评论家约翰·伯格
good without becoming propaganda in his
在他的
essays Revolutionary Undoing and The
文章《革命的解构》和《
Ideal Critic and The Fighting Critic.
理想的批评家与战斗的批评家》中探讨了艺术能否在不沦为宣传的情况下服务于社会福祉。
For Berger, this comes down to not the
在伯杰看来，这并非取决于
through a work of art, but the way the
艺术作品所传达的明确信息，而是取决于艺术家
work through how they craft a piece. I
如何通过创作作品将自己的视角编码到作品中。 我
think we see this reflected in the work
认为这一点在
of a director like Panahi, and those
帕纳希这样的导演的作品中有所体现，而这些
essays helped inform this video. You can
文章也为这部视频的制作提供了参考。 你可以
find them in this collection, which is
在这个合集中找到它们，这个合集是我
recent video I made giving a tour of all
最近制作的一个视频中提到的书籍之一，该视频介绍了
the film, media, and art books that I
我推荐的所有电影、媒体和艺术书籍
recommend.
。
that have informed my perspective over
多年来，有很多像这样的书籍影响了我的观点
the years, and I wanted a chance to talk
，我一直想有机会谈谈
about them. So, I've started a series of
它们。 所以，我开始制作一系列
videos to cover my favorites. Part one
视频来介绍我最喜欢的东西。 第一部分
is up right now, and part two will be up
现已上线，第二部分将于下个月上线
next month, both exclusively on Nebula.
，两部分均在 Nebula 独家播出。
While you're over on Nebula, you should
既然你去了 Nebula 网站，不妨也
check out all the other exclusive
看看那里的其他独家
content over there, including Cinema
内容，包括 Cinema
Stix series Let's Rewind, [music] which
Stix 系列的《Let's Rewind》[音乐]，该系列
covers the early careers of legendary
涵盖了
actors like Meryl Streep and Samuel L.
梅丽尔·斯特里普和塞缪尔·L·杰克逊等传奇演员的早期职业生涯
Jackson. There's also a ton of great
。  Nebula 还有许多精彩的
Nebula originals like the travel game
原创作品，例如
show Jet Lag, which I love, or Patrick
我非常喜欢的旅行游戏节目《时差》，以及 Patrick
H. Willems' [music] wildly entertaining
H. Willems 创作的极具娱乐性的
short film The Dinner Plan, with tons of
短片《晚餐计划》，而且还有大量
new originals coming all the time. On
新的原创作品不断推出。
top of that, you'll also get all my
除此之外，你还可以提前观看我的所有
regular videos early and completely
常规视频，而且完全
ad-free, along with a back catalog of
无广告，以及YouTube
exclusive video essays that aren't on
上没有的独家视频评论的往期内容
YouTube. Nebula is a completely ad-free
。  Nebula 是一个完全无广告的
streaming platform built and owned by
流媒体平台，由像
creators like me. It allows you to watch
我这样的创作者创建和拥有。 它让你能够观看
so much incredible thoughtful content
大量精彩且引人深思的内容，
while supporting the creators you love.
同时支持你喜爱的创作者。
So, jump into my book recommendations
所以，赶快来看看我的书籍推荐，
ad-free [music] when you sign up today.
今天注册即可提前观看我的下一个视频，而且没有广告和音乐。
When you use my link, you'll get 50% off
使用我的链接，您可享受 Nebula 50% 的折扣
of Nebula, which makes it just $30 a
，相当于每年只需 30 美元
year or $2.50 a month. [music] So, visit
或每月 2.50 美元。  [音乐] 所以，请访问
go.nebula.tv/thomasflight,
go.nebula.tv/thomasflight，
click the link in the description below,
点击下方描述中的链接，
or use the QR code on the screen today
或使用屏幕上的二维码，
to watch my bookshelf tour or any of
即可观看我的书架参观视频或
content on Nebula.
Nebula 上的其他精彩独家内容。[音乐]